ROSIE AFIA CV

Name: Rosie Afia

Contact: rosie@afia.london

Profile: British National I Full Driving License I Mother tongue English, Basic French & Spanish.

Highly articulate Development Management LSE graduate (MSc) with effective interpersonal skills. Experience demonstrates the capacity to be action-orientated, results-driven and use initiative in the face of time-sensitive objectives. Possesses the ability to multitask, respond to client requirements and a shows willingness to take responsibility down to the last detail.

Experience

LSE / Crown Agents, London.

Nov 2013 - Apr 2014

Student Research Consultant

- Developed LSE research report titled "Public Private Partnerships in Sub-Saharan Africa In Search of Critical Success Factors" for Crown Agents.
- Included case study analysis of public-private partnerships in three countries in Sub-Saharan Africa.
- Achievements: project expected to lead to partial fulfilment of Masters degree.

Fitch Learning, London.

Sep 2012 - Sep 2013

Client Liaison Assistant

- Bespoke courses team member for the specialist financial training company.
- Responsibilities included; general support to Managing Director, meeting coordination, micro-project management, presentations, assistance with internal / external client contacts, course schedule administration, assistance with course feedback & contracts.
- Achievements: after undertaking a temporary marketing assistant role in 2007 & 2008 was recruited to Client Liaison team. Supported senior management by temporarily acting in the more senior role as Client Liaison Officer while colleague on extended leave. Coordinated various time sensitive projects including extensive exposure to vital legal documentation.

Riad Chi-Chi, Marrakech.

Jul 2010 - Sep 2010

General Manager

- Responsible for administration, accounts, transport, guests & staff as holiday cover for manager.
- Achievements: received excellent published reviews / feedback from guests & employer.

African Impact (Social Enterprise) & THAF (NGO), Zambia.

Jun 2008 - Sep 2009

Project Designer & Coordinator (African Impact)

- Assisted local management, designed, implemented & managed the HIV & Sport volunteer project. Highly demanding, full-time & live-in job.
- Responsible for up to 30 volunteers, including organising trips to Zimbabwe / Botswana, coordinating staff, transport, visas & project administration.
- Achievements: designed & set-up HIV / Sport project to much acclaim from the community & volunteers. Founded "Livingstone Youth in Sport" charity in order to coordinate tournaments for HIV, malaria & drug awareness for children & women. As a result of the programme's success promoted to sister organisation, The Happy Africa Foundation (THAF).

Assistant Manager (THAF)

- Responsible for marketing, admin, accounts, operations & contracts for Zambia's sponsor-a-child scheme.
- Achievements: implementing efficient systems & procedures, including website design.
 Initiated process of providing regular feedback & updates for sponsors. Personal fundraising
 efforts totaled £4000 for the charity. As a result asked to be ambassador to Kenyan
 programme responsible for contracts & service level agreements for new projects. Created
 proposals for focal projects & initiated a sponsor-a-teacher programme.

Project Coordinator

- Responsible for invoicing / accounts, purchasing & various projects for CEO.
- Achievements: extensive responsibility as member of the accounts team regarding purchasing & payment of invoices. Completed a number of successful marketing projects for the CEO.

Internships / Volunteer Work

Society of Business Economists (SBE), London.

Sept 2013 - Current

 Paid administrative assistant to SBE secretary. Responsible for various projects such as council proposals, meeting coordination, internal communication & report compilations.

Buttons for Hope (NGO), Cape Town.

Mar 2011 - Apr 2011

 Responsible for social media & press exposure for start-up NGO. Established various online platforms for marketing & e-commerce supporting project sustainability.

Advance Aid (NGO), Nairobi & London.

Jul 2010 & Jul 2011

• As a part-time volunteer responsibilities included assisting CEO with vital meetings with the Kenyan Ministry of Health & researching grants.

Alive & Kicking (Charity), Nairobi & London.

Jun 2010 - Aug 2010

• Coordinated 2-day event (Arsenal in the Community) while based in Nairobi. Successfully raised US\$10,000 for the charity & asked to continue volunteer support on return to London.

Education & Qualifications

MSc Development Management, pending

2013-2014

London School of Economics (LSE).

BA Economics & Politics, First Class (Hons)

2009-2012

University of Leeds.

LSE & Nesta master class	Measuring Social Impact short course	Feb 2014
CodeFirst-Girls	10-week intensive website training course	Jan 2014
Fitch Learning short course	PowerPoint	Jul 2013
Fitch Learning short course	Excel	Jun 2013
Fitch Learning professional course	2-day course on understanding a structured approach to the analysis of Country & Sovereign risk in both emerging & mature markets.	Oct 2012
ONE Advocacy & Campaigns	2-day intensive training on running effective development campaigns.	Nov 2011

Hobbies & Other

- Software proficiency: Confluence, Dreamweaver CS6, Excel, GitHub, Lotus notes, Microsoft Word, Outlook, Powerpoint, SalesForce, SalesLogix, Social Media, SohoLaunch, Sublime Text, SourceTree, Windows & Mac OS systems among others.
- Representative for postgraduate Development Management students (LSE).
- Society of Business Economists (SBE) member since 2013.
- LSE societies: 'DESTIN', 'Business / Social Enterprise' & 'Women Leaders of Tomorrow'.
- Keen sports woman; BASI 2 instructor (snowboarding) qualification with first aid.
- Travelled extensively in Africa, Asia, Europe & Latin America.

References available on request.